<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Labyrinthe Rules</title><link>http://christiffer.github.io/labyrinthe-books/</link><description>Recent content on Labyrinthe Rules</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://christiffer.github.io/labyrinthe-books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>http://christiffer.github.io/labyrinthe-books/books/handbook/game-system/game-mechanics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://christiffer.github.io/labyrinthe-books/books/handbook/game-system/game-mechanics/</guid><description>Game Mechanics # Hand In The Air # A monster, or even a player, with his hand in the air is deemed not to be present in some fashion. They may be not currently playing a part, or being a part, which is invisible, or hidden, or supernaturally travelling (referred to as shifting) from one location to another. It generally means that you cannot interact with them and you should ignore their presence and not react to them in any fashion – roleplay as if you are not aware of them.</description></item><item><title>Grey Spells</title><link>http://christiffer.github.io/labyrinthe-books/books/grimoire/spells/grey/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://christiffer.github.io/labyrinthe-books/books/grimoire/spells/grey/</guid><description>Grey Spells # Standard Spells # 0 level spells # Detect Magic Level 0th Colour Grey Duration Instant Verbal I call upon the elements of fire, air, earth and water, reveal to me where you may be found... Detect magic! Description This spell indicates the location and shape of all things magical to the wizard. 1 level spells # Dispel Magic 1 Level 1st Colour Grey Duration Instant / 5 Minutes Verbal By my might dispel 1!</description></item><item><title>Money</title><link>http://christiffer.github.io/labyrinthe-books/books/handbook/game-system/equiptment/money/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://christiffer.github.io/labyrinthe-books/books/handbook/game-system/equiptment/money/</guid><description>Money ~ Grulls # The in-character currency of The Empire is the grull, which comes in denominational notes from 10G to 5000G in value.
A day&amp;rsquo;s adventuring will earn you between a couple of hundred and a few thousand grulls, depending on your level. This could be in the form of pay from the merchant who hires you to rescue his daughter, or treasure looted from an ogre&amp;rsquo;s horde. Grulls can be spent on:</description></item><item><title>Physical Armour Class - PAC</title><link>http://christiffer.github.io/labyrinthe-books/books/handbook/game-system/amour-class/pac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://christiffer.github.io/labyrinthe-books/books/handbook/game-system/amour-class/pac/</guid><description>Physical Armour Class ~ PAC # PAC is armour that protects from physical attacks. Certain races, notably Trolls, have evolved tough hides or bony plate coverings that innately grant PAC as a natural protection, but PAC is usually dependant on the type of armour that you wear.
Advantages of PAC # As long as you are wearing the armour it will apply to blows made by a weapon with a physical component.</description></item><item><title/><link>http://christiffer.github.io/labyrinthe-books/books/handbook/game-system/combat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://christiffer.github.io/labyrinthe-books/books/handbook/game-system/combat/</guid><description>Combat # As previously mentioned Labyrinthe is an Heroic System. As a result the basic combat system is not a simple 1 hit affair. One of the advantages of a Heroic System is that you don’t actually have to have the martial prowess of an Olympic fencer to be able to enjoy yourself. The chances of your character surviving a combat are enhanced by your choice of Class, Race and the armour that you wear.</description></item><item><title>Armour</title><link>http://christiffer.github.io/labyrinthe-books/books/handbook/game-system/equiptment/armour/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://christiffer.github.io/labyrinthe-books/books/handbook/game-system/equiptment/armour/</guid><description>Armour # Armour Below are listed the cost of purchasing armour in grulls. The cost of armour is calculated by the actual AC it grants. E.G. Mastercrafted AC 2 costs the same as AC 4
Body Armour 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 Head 20 40 60 80 100 120 140 160 Chest or Abdomen 30 60 90 120 150 180 210 240 Upper or lower legs / arms 10 20 30 40 50 60 70 80 Complete Suit 160 320 480 640 800 960 1120 1280 For example: A complete suit of light chain mail, which grants AC 4 and lasts for 5 adventures, costs 640 Grulls, where as a complete suit of Master crafted light chain mail, which grants AC 6 and lasts for 10 adventures, costs 960 Grulls.</description></item><item><title>Dexterity Armour Class - DAC</title><link>http://christiffer.github.io/labyrinthe-books/books/handbook/game-system/amour-class/dac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://christiffer.github.io/labyrinthe-books/books/handbook/game-system/amour-class/dac/</guid><description>Dexterity Armour Class ~ DAC # DAC represents a characters ability to dodge a blow, to simply not be there when it lands, to roll with it or to twist and turn such that it merely glances off them without injury. Certain races, notably Goblins, are naturally highly dextrous and certain classes, such as Scouts, have agility bonuses.
Advantages of DAC # As long as the character is able to freely move his body then it applies to any weapon blow including supernatural ones such as a purely magical sword or a purely spiritual Mace.</description></item><item><title>Wizard</title><link>http://christiffer.github.io/labyrinthe-books/tables/class/wizard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://christiffer.github.io/labyrinthe-books/tables/class/wizard/</guid><description>Wizardly Post 8th Abilities # Table 1 # Ability Description Cost Available To Innate Spells Wizard or Warlock may elect to learn some of their spells innately, such that they can be cast without any mana point cost, but still with any associated life point cost. Only handbook or basic spells that are already known by the spell caster may be chosen, and they must be either of their own colours or grey - a Red Wizard cannot learn Dancing Venom Sword innately, or even Disintegrate (range).</description></item><item><title>Magical Armour Class - MAC</title><link>http://christiffer.github.io/labyrinthe-books/books/handbook/game-system/amour-class/mac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://christiffer.github.io/labyrinthe-books/books/handbook/game-system/amour-class/mac/</guid><description>Magical Armour Class ~ MAC # MAC is generally created through use of Spells. Certain races, notably Elves, have evolved the ability to create MAC as a natural protection
Spell Defence # Each point of MAC protects against 6/1 of a magical blast-type spell’s damage. It stops 6pts of TBLP damage and 1pt to each Location. Against targeted spells like Shock it applies just as PAC does to a weapon blow – each point of MAC stops 1pt of damage.</description></item><item><title>Weapons</title><link>http://christiffer.github.io/labyrinthe-books/books/handbook/game-system/equiptment/weapons/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://christiffer.github.io/labyrinthe-books/books/handbook/game-system/equiptment/weapons/</guid><description> Weapons #</description></item><item><title>Spiritual Armour Class - SAC</title><link>http://christiffer.github.io/labyrinthe-books/books/handbook/game-system/amour-class/sac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://christiffer.github.io/labyrinthe-books/books/handbook/game-system/amour-class/sac/</guid><description>Spiritual Armour Class ~ SAC # SAC is generally created through use of Miracles. Miracle Defence: Each point of SAC protects against 6/1 of a Miracle’s damage if that miracles harms every location. It stops 6 pts of TBLP damage and 1pt to each Location. For Example
The Evil Miracle Cause Grievous Wounds inflicts 36/5, i. e.miracle hits someone with SAC 1 then they only suffer 30/4 damage. 36 TBLP and 5 to each location.</description></item><item><title>Supernatural Armour</title><link>http://christiffer.github.io/labyrinthe-books/books/handbook/game-system/amour-class/supernatural-armour/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://christiffer.github.io/labyrinthe-books/books/handbook/game-system/amour-class/supernatural-armour/</guid><description>Supernatural Armour # It is possible for normal physical armour to be empowered with supernatural energy, either Magical or Spiritual. In this case it might be referred to as +0 Magic Armour or +0 Spirit Armour. A suit of armour so empowered offers some supernatural protection. Additionally it cannot be destroyed by normal magical or spiritual means that would destroy a mundane object. +0 Magical Armour allows the AC value to be applied versus purely magical weapon blows.</description></item></channel></rss>